CLAYTON GWAVA

Harare

csgwava@gmail.com +263771222585

Skilled, dedicated Systems Engineer with over two years of experience in Data analytics, Java programming, Python, C and C++, MySQL, database administration, Support Systems operation and Information security. In the telecommunications industry I have worked in Core Systems Engineering, Access Systems Engineering, Solution designs and project management.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

WORK EXPERIENCE

Core Systems Planning Engineer

Econet Wireless Zimbabwe

June 2019 to Present

Duties: Capacity planning, systems roadmap, solution design, innovations, projects' technical documentations

Graduate Service and Support System Engineer

Econet Wireless Zimbabwe - Harare

March 2019 to May 2019

Services and support systems planning, low level designs, high level designs and projects oversights.

Graduate Information Security Analyst

Econet Wireless Zimbabwe - Harare

January 2019 to February 2019

Creating security policies and monitoring systems that support them. Data protection from database level to access level.

Graduate System Support Operations Engineer

Econet Wireless Zimbabwe - Harare

November 2018 to December 2018

Providing platforms for monitoring the telecommunications and the IT network infrastructure. Providing systems support on all network elements

Radio Frequency and Access Systems Planning Engineer

Econet Wireless Zimbabwe - Harare

July 2018 to October 2018

Planning of radio frequencies and embracing telecoms technologies. Planning new radio sites and site survey.

Electrical Engineering Intern

Zimbabwe Electricity Transmission and Distribution Company Meter -

Conducted an industrial attachment as an Assistant technician.

Boss Mining S.p.r.I (DRC)

Conducted an industrial attachment as an Electrical and Electronic Engineering attaché.

PROJECTS EXPERIENCE

Project Name: APP5 project

(From July 2018)

A system that concatenate all network statistics into one storage system then provide visual analytics through Qlik sense enterprise for ease of access by anyone with login rights.

Project Name: Automated Report Generation

(From November 2018)

Proposed a system that automatically generates csv files and append daily health checks of servers then sends to the department via emails.

Electrical Engineering Projects

Project Name: Design and building of a Smart Electricity Meter

(September 2016 - May 2017)

Designed a smart electricity metering system which enable users to buy electricity using theiR mobile phones just like they buy airtime.

EDUCATION

Project Management in Project Management

University of Zimbabwe - Harare July 2019 to Present

Bachelor's in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

The University of Zimbabwe - Harare

September 2013 to May 2017

- Enthusiastic
- Attentive to detail
- Great Analytical and problem Solving Skills
- Good communication skills (Toastmasters club member)
- Team player
- Responsible Clayton Gwava Clayton Gwava
- Scripting
- Skilled in all Unix
- Maria DBX, MySQL, Hadoop, Mongo DB
- Columnstore database
- Data analytics
- Technical Documents design
- Project Management (Waterfall and Agile)
- End to End Project documentation
- Capacity Management
- Network Planning
- Network Administration

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Driver's License

April 2018 to Present

I have a ZImbabwe's class 2 license for Trucks and small motor vehicles.

Hadoop for Data Science

March 2019 to Present

Preparation course for Hadoop

Networking Foundations

February 2019 to Present

Data Science Tools of the Trade

April 2019 to Present

Windows 10: Plan and Implement Software Updates

May 2019 to Present

May 2019 to Present
Networking Foundations: Protocols and CLI Tools
March 2019 to Present
MySQL for Advanced Analytics
March 2019 to Present
Learning SSH
June 2019 to Present
Learning Splunk
May 2019 to Present
Learning Splunk
September 2018 to Present
IT Service Desk
September 2018 to Present
Implementing an Information Security Program
October 2018 to Present
Hadoop: Data Analysis
November 2018 to Present
CompTIA Network+ (N10-007) Cert Prep: 1 Understanding Networks August 2018 to Present
CISM Cert Prep: 1 Information Security Governance
Present

Twelve Myths About Data Science